A constant pain, once a month, takes me to
một cơn đau cứ liên tục mỗi tháng một
the emergency room. It
lần lên bệnh viện cấp cứu nó hành hạ cơ
torments my body, causing excruciating pain, and
thể đau đớn đau đau là đau quắn quại mà
it always happens at 11 or 12 midnight. Oh, and the
nó lại toán vào 11 12:00 đêm ch cô ạ nến
doctor said, "Oh, this woman again! If it were someone
lỗi bác sĩ bảo này chứ Ôi lại cái bà này
like this, the hospital would never have
ai như cái bà này thì bệnh viện chả bao
doctors who would be out of work."
giờ bác sĩ nó thất
[Music] I
[âm nhạc]
respectfully greet the Headmistress. I
nghiệp con xin kính chào cô chủ nhiệm
respectfully greet all fellow practitioners and
Xin kính chào quý đạo hữu cùng tất cả
friends. Next, I would like to introduce a
các bạn sau đây Con xin giới thiệu một
story of a transformation through the application of
câu chuyện Chuyển Nghiệp nhờ ứng dụng
Buddhist teachings, demonstrating the miraculous healing of
phật pháp thể hiện sự linh ứng trong
abdominal pain
việc điều trị khỏi bệnh đau bụng chẩn
diagnosed by adhesions in the case of Buddhist follower Nguyen Thi
đoán dính ruột của cô phật tử Nguyễn Thị
Thanh from Minh Hiep Yen The Buddhist Center.
thành thuộc Đạo Tràng Minh Hiệp Yên Thế
I respectfully invite Ms. Nguyen Thi
sau đây Con xin kính mời cô Nguyễn Thị
Thanh to share her story.
Thành lên chia sẻ câu chuyện của mình
Respectfully, Headmistress. Dear
ạ Kính bạch cô chủ nhiệm ạ Kính thưa
fellow practitioners, I am Nguyen Thi Thanh,
toàn thể đạo hữu tôi ngyễn thị thành năm
67 years old. In
nay 67 tuổi tôi năm
2004, I had surgery for uterine fibroids, a
2004 tôi đi mổ u sơ tử cung cắt
total ovaryectomy, and a
a toàn phần phụ cắt u sơ tử cung cắt một
polypectomy. Then, in
cái pô
2006, I had another painful surgery to
2006 tôi lại một trận mổ đau đớn nữa là
remove adhesions, cut the ligaments, and remove the appendix.
gỡ dính ruột cắt dây Trằng cắt ruột thừa
Then, around 2012, I
thế sau đến khi năm 2012 thì à tôi người
felt like I was dying.
cứ như là ai u tưởng là lúc B giờ chết ý
Suddenly, I turned pale, lay listlessly, could
tự nhiên là ra cứ vàng bệch ra nằm quay
n't sit up, and was in terrible pain. My
là cứ đừ ra không ngồi không ấy được đau
children
đớn cọ đau đớn lắm thế mà xong đi con nó
took me to Bach Mai Hospital for examination,
mới đưa đi Bắc bệnh viện Bạch Mai khám
but they only did
thì về bệnh viện Bạch Mai thì chỉ xét
tests and couldn't find anything wrong. They just
nghiệm là chỉ khám không ra bệnh gì mà
said my blood pressure was a little high and my
chỉ bảo rằng là hơi áp huyết hơi cao này
diabetes was slightly elevated. After that, my
à tiểu đường hơi hơi lên Thế xong rồi về
hands hurt so much I couldn't lift them, my
thì tay thì nó cứ đau không Giơ được lên
legs ached, and I could only walk
thế này chân thì nó buốt cứ đi bộ đ được
a few steps before needing to be patted again. Then, I kept
vài đối lại cứ vỗ này vỗ này mới lại đi
going to
được thế xong cứ suốt ngày là đi lên
Tan Yen District Hospital.
bệnh viện huyện tấn Yên Thôi lúc B giờ
After Bach Mai, they couldn't find anything wrong, but the
đi khám ở Bạch Mai không Bệnh gì thì cứ
pain just kept going to Tan Yen District Hospital for
đau đớn như thế lên bệnh viện huyện Tân
traditional medicine. The doctors there
Yên vào đông y thì bác sĩ bệnh viện Đông
concluded it was rheumatoid arthritis, so they just prescribed acupuncture and
luận là à viêm khớp thấp nên là cứ châm
electroacupuncture. I stayed at that
cứu thì điện châm rồi thì cứ nằm ở Bệnh
hospital about three times a year. Then, in
viện ấy cứ một năm thì lên độ ba lần
2014,
trên Bệnh viện ấy thế đến năm 2014 thì
it started
nó lại à
tormenting me again.  Every now and then I would have
à hành hạ coi là Cứ thỉnh thoảng lại đau
stomach pains and go to Hanoi Medical University Hospital for a
bụng sang Bệnh viện Đại học Y Hà Nội
general check-up, but they found nothing wrong,
khám tổng thể thì không có bệnh gì thế
so they told me to go home. Then, whenever I had stomach pains, I would go to the
thì bác sĩ bảo cho về Thế cứ đau bụng
hospital in Ta Yen,
thì lại lên bệnh viện tấ Yên lên bệnh
and they said it was just a persistent symptom,
viện tấ yên thì bảo chỉ có hiện tượng
nothing serious. So I just kept getting IV fluids. In
dững rệt đấ chả có bệnh gì cả Thế là cứ
2014, I tried traditional
truyền nước đây năm 2014 thì cứ nên đông
medicine, but the pain persisted. My legs and arms hurt,
y chữa được nó cứ đau Chân đau tay như
but it didn't go away. In
thế nhưng mà nó không khỏi đến năm
2016, the pain became constant,
2016 thì một cơn đau cứ liên tục mỗi
once a month, and I had to go to the emergency room. It turned into
tháng một lần lên bệnh viện cấp cứu nó
excruciating pain, a
thành hạ cơ thể đau đớn đau đau là đau
agonizing, agonizing pain that always started around 11 or 12
quăn quại mà nó lại toán vào 11 12:00
midnight. It would
đêm thôi cô ạ cứ bắt đầu chập tối ăn cơm
only be a slight ache when I ate dinner. My
thì nó chỉ hơi hơi nhăm nhẩm thế Thế có
child said, "Mom, you have
con nó bảo mẹ ơi mẹ lại hiện tượng dính
intestinal adhesions again!" The doctor said, "Just keep
ruột rồi bác sĩ bảo thế thì thôi mẹ cứ
getting IV fluids."
đi truyền nước Xem bảo hượng mẹ đau ít
But every night around 11 PM, I would
lắm thế nhưng mà cứ đến 11 giờ đêm một
start feeling dizzy and nauseous,
cái là bắt đầu người nó quay cuồng thế
unable to walk. The pain was so intense, I was sweating profusely, and my whole
này cứ Bo này Bo này không đi nổi nữa Bo
body was trembling.
nó đau mồ hôm nó vã ra C hất đầm người
Then she said, "Oh my god, let's
cứ run run thế này Thế xong bảo con ơi
go to the hospital, otherwise I'll
Thôi đi lên bệnh viện đi chứ không mẹ
die!" She went to the hospital and
chết mất đi Thế lên bệnh viện đến nỗi mà
had to wear diapers. Her daughter-in-law took her
phải đóng bỉm Thế con dâu nó đưa lên nó
there and said, "Mom, you can't control yourself
bảo này chứ mẹ ơi thế Mẹ không làm chủ
anymore, you still have to pee in your pants!" Then she said, "It's just that it
được nữa mẹ vẫn phải đái ch quần à Xong
hurts, Mom, and she just keeps doing
bả không Mỗi là nó đau của mẹ thì nó lại
it. I know what I'm doing, but sometimes it happens every
xá ra đấy chứ mẹ có vẫn là biết mà có
20 days, sometimes once a
lúc thì 20 ngày lại một lần có lúc thì 1
month." Then the doctor on duty
tháng một lần nến lỗi bác sĩ trực ở khám
at the hospital said, "Oh my god, it's so painful!" If
ở bệnh viện thân yên ấy bảo này chứ Ôi
everyone were
giời ra ngói Ôi lại cái bà này ai cũng
like this woman, the
như cái bà này thì bệnh viện chả bao giờ
doctors at the hospital would never be out of work. It's so bad,
bác sĩ nó thất nghiệp mà vì hay đi quá
every 20 days she's tormented by
cứ 20 ngày một lần mà nó hành hạ cơn đau
stomach pain. Each time it hurts, it's a terrible pain, a
đau bụng Mỗi một lần l đau đau đở đau
agonizing pain. She's in so much pain, she vomits, and her
quăn quại Đau Khổ ra đau đau là cứ nôn
child takes her to the hospital, and she vomits all the way there, screaming and throwing up. When she
là con nó đèo đi là nô nôn cứ dọc đường
gets to the hospital, she has to
nôn cứ thét quần này lên bệnh viện là
bring several sets of clothes, and she
bao giộng phải mang theo vài bộ quần áo
keeps vomiting, throwing up water all the way, and when she vomits, it's a
nó cứ nôn tóe nước ra đi mà đến lúc nôn
bloody mess. At the hospital, they
dãy xánh dãy vàng ra nên bệnh viện là
give her an IV drip, a butterfly needle.  When they
người ta truyền vào kim lùa Kim cánh
put the needle in my hand, it
bướm ấ vào tay này cho ấy thì đến nỗi mà
hurt so much I was writhing in pain, writhing and crawling around, bending over.
đau đến nỗi vật vã cứ vò rồi bò rồ khom
The needle bent into a figure eight, and I did
cái kim số tám nó quăn thành số tám cái
n't feel any pain, I didn't
kim lùa ấy mà không biết đau là gì không
feel any pain in my hand. The next day, it got
biết đau tay là gì đến hôm sau xong nó
clogged again, they
là người ta nó lại tắc chuyền nước nó
removed the needle, and then,
tắc người ta lại tháo kim ta đến năm
in 2017, I had a
nhân duyên đến năm 2017 à Có một cô em
cousin. She said, "Sister Thanh, did you go on the
họ Cô bảo là Chị Thành ơi chị có đi mùng
4th day of Tet? The 8th day of Tet, you went to
4 Tết mùng B Tết là đi đi đi đi chơi
visit the temples." I replied, "Oh,
xuân đi đi các chùa ấy Thế thì bảo là ô
I don't know what Ba Vang Temple is like.
Chị chưa biết chùa Bá Vàng thế nào Người
People say Ba Vang Temple is very beautiful, but I've
ta bảo là có chùa Bá Vàng đẹp lắm mà chị
never been there before." I went to
chưa được về bao giờ đâu em ạ tôi mới đi
Ba Vang Temple on January 4th, 2017, and
chùa Bá Vàng hôm mùng 4 tháng 1 năm 2017
she said, "There's a monk who kidnaps boys in the gold mining area." I
xong mới nó bảo ở chỗ phá vàng có tu bắt
listened to the
con trai đấy chị ạ xuống dưới này Nghe
monk's lecture and realized that I was also affected by
sư phụ giảng mới biết là mình cũng bị
karma, that
cái nhân quả cho nên là cũng biết là cái
my past actions of doing
nghiệp của mình trước kia nó làm những
evil were causing me to
việc ác cho nên là bây giờ phải chịu nó
suffer pain and torment. Every time I thought about it, I had to go to the hospital.
hành hạ đau đớn Cứ mỗi một trận nghĩ lên
Every month I had to go to the hospital.  So, when it was time to go back to practice Buddhism, I came
lên Tháng nào cũng phải lên viện thế đến
here to practice, then went home to practice the
lúc về tu về đây tu xong về nhà tu quản
number eight. Yes, then I made offerings, then repented.
số tám Vâng xong rồi cúng dường Rồi khám
Thanks to the miraculous power of Buddhism, from
hối Thế là nhờ được Phật Pháp Nhiệm Màu
2017 until now, my
xong đến tư 2017 cho đến tận à bây giờ
leg and arm pains are gone, and my
coi bệnh đau chân đau tay nó cũng đâu
stomach aches are gone too. I haven't had to
hết ấ rồi bệnh đau bụng nó ấy không phải
go to the hospital a single day. This is truly the miraculous power of Buddhism. Even my
đi viện một ngày nào đâ là đúng là là là
neighbors, my cousins, my uncles, and my aunts next door
cái cô em họ con chú con bác bên cạnh
said, "Sister, you're really suited to Ba Vang Pagoda!"
bảo này chứ chị đúng là hợp với chùa Ba
Then I said, "Oh, everyone said, 'Let
rồi Thế xong bảo à mọi người bảo à đi
me go to Ba Vang Pagoda!' I said, 'Okay,' and my son
cho em đi chùa Ba Vàng mới nhá bảo ừ thế
said, "Oh, Mom, since going to
con trai bảo này Ôi mẹ từ ngày đi chùa
Ba Vang Pagoda, I don't know how,
Ba Vàng là thế nào chả biết thế nào
but I haven't had to go to the hospital!"
nhưng mà không phải đi viện nhỉ Thế xong
Then he said, "Ah, yes, the miraculous power of Buddhism is amazing!" My
rồi lúc bảo là à đấy Phật Pháp Nhiệm Màu
husband, who
lắm ông xã nhà em là lúc ngày xưa thì
used to go to the hospital all the time, said, "When I was
ông ấy cứ lên bệnh viện thì ông bảo lúc
sick, I was always sick and in
lao cũng đau mới ốm người đúng là người
pain. Since going to the pagoda, he
mới đau sẽ từ ngày đi chùa đến giờ ông
says, 'What do you want to do? Just do whatever makes you feel
bảo bà muốn làm nào làm bà cứ cứ thấy nó
healthy.' So, my husband and children
khỏe thì bà làm cho nên là cả chồng con
support me a lot."  Last year, I
tạo điều kiện cho lắm coay 3 năm vừa rồi
didn't have to miss a single day of the lunar month, and I was so happy I
mà không phải bỏ chỉ sướng thế là không
never had to miss a single day of the Eight Precepts. It's truly
bao giờ phải bỏ một ngày mùng tá nàoi đi
thanks to the miraculous power of Buddhism.
đều đạn th Bát Quan Trai Đúng là nhờ có
I must express my
Phật Pháp Nhiệm Màu Em phải xin được tri
gratitude to my master, the great monks of Ba Vang Pagoda, and
ân sư phụ cùng đại tăng chùa Ba Vàng và
Ms. Pham Thi Yen, the head of the group, for their guidance and
cô chủ nhiệm Phạm Thị Yến thách tấn chỉ
instruction in practice. Now, I no longer experience
dạy tu tập đến bản thân em bây giờ chả
any pain in my body and don't have to
còn đau đớn gì trong cơ thể không phải
go to the hospital a single day. It's so wonderful,
lên bệnh viện ngày nào là rất sung sướng
the whole family is happy, my children and
cả nhà cùng sung sướng con cháu chồng
grandchildren are all excited. That's all I have to
con rồi thì đều phấn khởi thế nên xin
say. And respectfully, dear fellow practitioners, let's
hết ý kiến ạ à Kính thưa các quý đạo hữu
take the case of this gentleman, who was
lấy trường hợp của bác là một trường hợp
once ill, over 60 years old. His illness was chronic,
có lúc bị bệnh đã có tuổi ngoài 60 bệnh
nothing
như thế là Triền Miên không Cái gì là
compares to stomach pain. When you have stomach pain,
bằng cái bệnh đau bụng đã đau bụng rồi
eating and digestion are very
thì ăn uống cái tiêu hóa nó cũng rất là
poor, right? It's so painful, the pain is unbearable. For
kém phải không khổ lắm đau đau đ nó cứ
example, with pain
bò cnh bò càng ra vì là ví dụ Đau chỗ
elsewhere, we can still eat
khác ấy thì chúng ta còn có thể ăn uống
a little, right? But with stomach pain, you
được một chút phải không Nhưng đau bụng
can't eat at all, it's so painful. Honestly,
thì không thể ăn được rất đau thực sự là
when he talks about it, we can
khi bác nói thì chúng ta có thể cười
only laugh, but if we experienced it ourselves,
được thôi chứ còn nếu chúng ta mà đau
we wouldn't be able to eat at all.
thử xem không thể nào mà chúng ta còn
What other emotion besides this pain is
cái cảm xúc gì khác ngoài cái đau này
there? It hurts so much. So, practicing
đâu đau lắm Thế thì cái việc tu tập Phật
Buddhism to transform this pain is
pháp để chuyển hóa được cái bệnh đau này
truly a diligent effort. Yes,
thì quả thật cũng là một sự tinh tấn
diligent practice is necessary for
Vâng tinh tấn tu thì nó mới có chuyển
transformation, and it must have faith. Faith,
hóa và nó phải có cái lòng tin lòng tin
because you've been to every hospital,
bởi vì là bác đã đi hết bệnh viện rồi
taken every medicine, and run out of options.
rồi uống cái thuốc rồi Hết chỗ rồi cho
So, only those who have gone everywhere
nên cái người nào phải nói là đi hết chỗ
have faith in Buddhism.
rồi mới có lòng tin và phật pháp chứ
People who are either not sick yet, or
người ta còn thứ nhất là chưa bệnh đâu
sick but cured by medicine,
thứ hai là có bệnh nhưng đi chữa thuốc
don't believe in Buddhism, right, dear fellow
khỏi thì chưa tin phật pháp đâu phải
practitioners? Only when there's
không các quý đạo hữu Thì chỉ bao giờ mà
no other way to
không còn đường nào để khiến cho mình
survive do they turn to Buddhism.
sống được nữa rồi thì mới tìm về Phật
Some people ask, "
có những người thì hỏi thế này
Practicing Buddhism is so
ạ bảo rằng là đi tu Phật là nó sung
blissful and happy. Why
sướng hạnh phúc thế Tại sao con Phật lại
are Buddhist followers mostly people who see suffering,
toàn là những người mà thấy là khổ th
poverty, hardship, and
thấy là nghèo thấy là khổ thấy là bệnh
illness? Those are the only Buddhist disciples;
tật toàn thế đệ tử Phật là những người
few are happy."
như thế chứ ít người được sung sướng thì
My answer is that when people are
mình cũng trả lời luôn đó là khi còn
happy, few seek out Buddhism
sung sướng thì ít người tìm đến Đạo Phật
because only those with good karma from
bởi vì chỉ có người có thiện căn từ kiếp
previous lives, when they are happy,  They've
trước thôi thì khi đang sung sướng thì
only recently come to Buddhism, but in reality,
mới tìm đến Đạo Phật thôi chứ còn thực
these Buddhists are mostly people who have reached the end of their rope, with
ra ấ phật tử ấy thì toàn là những người
nowhere
hết chỗ cứu rồi không còn chỗ nào cứu
else to turn for help. They come to the Buddhist home because they've
nữa rồi thì mới về đến nhà Phật thì một
faced numerous hardships, including illness, loss of possessions, and children –
là gặp phải những cái lạn bệnh tật tài
in fact, they've
lắm thực chất là có những nơi có khi họ
gone to many places, offered sacrifices, and lost all their possessions
đi hết tất nơi cúng hết rồi tài sản hết
before coming to the Buddhist home. That's why
rồi mới về đến nhà Phật thế cho nên là
the Buddha called the
Đức Phật gọi
Dharma the Dharma of salvation from
là giáo pháp của Phật là giáo pháp cứu
suffering. They only come here when they're suffering; if they're happy, they'll be carefree, enjoying themselves, and having everything they want. Only when they're in
khổ mà cứ khổ thì mới về đây còn sung
extreme pain and have
đủ thứ chỉ có khổ quá Hết chỗ rồi về đây
nowhere else to go do they find salvation. That's why Buddhists are those who are called sincere and devoted. Because at that point, they have no other choice; they've reached the end of their rope.
còn tâm để đi đâu nữa rồi Hết chỗ cứu
Through your story, we
rồi thì qua cái câu chuyện của Bác thì
can see that all kinds of illnesses, if they
mới thấy là tất cả các loại bệnh nếu như
haven't yet fallen into a state of karmic retribution,
chưa rơi vào định nghiệp thì tu tập nó
can be transformed through practice. What does it mean to fall into a state of karmic retribution?
đều chuyển hóa Thế nào là rơi vào định
It means that when one's body is
nghiệp tức là khi cơ thể của mình bị phá
completely destroyed, then there's
tan nát hết rồi thì cái lúc bấy giờ tu
no time left to
thì nó không kịp cái thời gian chuyển
transform the karma. That is, if
hóa được cái cái cái nghiệp nữa Tức là
one were to practice, it would be too late.  It's like
đáng ra mình tu cũng giống như là mình
planting a cabbage. You sow the seeds, you plant
trồng cái cây cải ấy mà Thì reo nó hạt
them in the ground, and even with the
nó xuống dưới đất thật đấy thế nhưng nó
right season and plenty of water and
đúng mùa vụ này thế rồi có đầy đủ nước
care, it still takes 15 days before the
tưới chăm bón này cũng phải 15 ngày mới
plant is ready to eat. If our illness
được cây mà ăn thế nếu như cái bệnh của
only
chúng ta ấ mà cơ thể của chúng ta nó chỉ
partially damages our body, there's enough time for
bị phá một phần thôi nó đủ thời gian để
our practice to take hold, and then it
thấm cái việc tu tập của chúng ta thì nó
can be completely transformed. But if death is
mới chuyển hết được thế nhưng mà cái
imminent, meaning the illness has already
chết nó đã cận kề rồi Tức là cái bệnh nó
destroyed everything and death is close, then it's
phá hết rồi cái chết cận kề rồi mà lúc
very difficult to transform at that point. Then there are
bấy giờ mới tu thì rất là khó chuyển Thế
illnesses where death is imminent. These
còn có những cái bệnh cái chết cận kề Đó
are illnesses that occur
là những cái bệnh mà nó chỉ xảy ra đột
suddenly, meaning the body is
ngột thôi tức là cơ thể người ta hãy
healthy, and then it happens suddenly.
khỏe xong người ta có thể xảy ra đột
At that time, if they practice, they
ngột thế đột ngột thì lúc bấy giờ người
can make vows to the Buddha, cultivate diligently, and dedicate merit to
ta ta có thể tu bạch Phật phát nguyện tu
doing good deeds.
dũng mãnh phát tâm làm phước hồi hướng
Because their body isn't completely damaged, they're only
thì do cơ thể của họ chưa Hỏng họ chỉ bị
slightly affected. They can then
một chút đi Thôi thì họ có thể chuyển
transform their karma;
hóa được cái nghiệp tức là họ do tăng
because they've increased their merit, they can transform their karma and
phước cho nên họ chuyển hóa được nghiệp
recover. The same applies to your case,
thì họ sẽ khỏi thì trường hợp này của
because you've practiced.  As
bác cũng thế do mình có tu tập trên cái
one's merit increases, so does
Phước báo của mình nó tăng lên thì cái
one's karma.
Phước báo của mình lên thì cái nghiệp nó
In the
tiêu đi và cái trong cái chương trình tu
eighth practice program, which focuses on
tập bài số tám là chương trình tu tập
repentance towards karmic enemies, according to
sám hối với oan gia chế chủ thì với tinh
Buddhist principles, if we commit
thần của nhà Phật chúng ta có làm việc
evil deeds, we create karmic debt. The
ác thì chúng ta tạo oán kết cho nên Đức
Buddha taught that among the eight sufferings, there is one
Phật dạy trong tám khổ ấ nó có một cái
suffering called the suffering of karmic enemies
khổ đó là oán tắng hội khổ tức là có oán
gathering in one place.
đối mà hội tụ một nơi thì là khổ thế cho
Therefore, when one suffers from illness, it signifies that
nên khi mà mình mang thân bệnh ấ là đủ
in a previous life, one caused suffering to sentient beings.
duyên Khi mà mình kiếp trước mình làm
Now, they are reborn in
khổ chúng sinh Thế đến nay họ sinh trong
the realm of hungry ghosts and seek revenge.
cõi ngã quỷ họ về họ báo oán mình thì
This is called the gathering of karmic debt, causing
đây gọi là hội tụ một chỗ có oán kết
suffering to one another.
nhưng hội tụ một chỗ gây khổ cho nhau
For those practicing the eighth practice, one must
trên người tu tập bài Số tám ấy là phải
actively repent of
nỗ lực tích cực sám hối các tội chướng
their sins and believe that the realm of
của mình và phải tin rằng có cõi vong
hungry ghosts surrounds them and they
linh ngã quỷ ở xung quanh mình và họ
are seeking revenge. Therefore, one must actively
đang báo oán mình tro nên mình tích cực
repent to them daily at home, twice a day,
sám hối họ hàng ngày ở nhà một ngày phải
sometimes even three times. One must also make offerings to the Three Jewels, dedicating
hai thời sám hối có khi còn ba thời phải
merit and praying for
không cúng dường tam bảo hồi hướng phúc
their liberation so that they do not gather together.
lành cầu siêu độ cho họ họ không hội tụ
With me, there's another place. So I
với mình một chỗ nữa Thế là mình giải
resolved this resentment and
quyết được cái oán đối này và mình
transformed my illness. The vengeful spirit's actions
chuyển hóa được bệnh tật câu oan raia
are like this: Resentment brings suffering
chá chủ nó là như thế đấy Oán tắng hội
and it's like I caused
khổ và oan ra chế chủ nó còn là mình làm
them suffering in a previous life, and
cho họ oan uổng khổ sở kiếp trước bây
now they come back to take revenge, acting against
giờ họ về đây họ báo oán họ làm trái ý
my wishes. For example, if I pray for good health, they
mình Ví dụ mình cầu mạnh khỏe thì họ
make me sick. If I pray for happiness,
khiến cho mình ốm Mình cầu hạnh phúc thì
they make me suffer. If I pray for wealth,
họ khiến cho mình đau khổ mình cầu Giàu
they make me fail. For instance, if
có thì họ khiến cho mình thất bát ví dụ
I beat them in a previous life,
kiếp trước mình đánh đập trên thân thể
they will cause me illness if I pray for good health. If I
của họ thì đến nay mình cầu khỏe thì họ
stole their property in a previous life, and
trước mình trộm cắp tài sản của họ đến
I pray for wealth in this life, they
kiếp này mình cầu mình làm ăn giàu có
will lead me astray, causing
thì họ sẽ dẫn dắt mình khiến cho mình có
me to lose my
duyên khiến cho mình bị thất thoát tài
wealth. One is to make me suffer again, the other is to
sản Một là khiến cho mình lợ lần hai là
make me associate with bad friends, leading to
khiến cho mình chơi bời với bạn ác nhiều
financial loss. That's what's
để cho mình thất thoát tài sản Thế mới
called a vengeful spirit's actions, that's what's called a vengeful spirit's actions in a
gọi là oan giai ch chủ mới gọi là có oán
previous life. If I wronged them in a previous life, they come back to
đối kiếp trước kiếp trước mình làm oan
act against my wishes when
họ kiếp này họ về làm trái ý mình khi
I pray for happiness.  So,
mình mong cầu cái điều hạnh phúc thế thì
in this case, it's due to
ở đây là một trường hợp của bác là do
intestinal adhesions, and I have
bệnh dính ruột ạ và em còn một chuyện
another story. Last January, 2019,
này nữa ạ tháng riêng Năm ngoái là 2019
I suddenly had a hoarse voice for a whole month and could
ạ Em tự nhiên một tháng trời khản đặc
n't speak. Then I went home and
tiếng không nói được Thế xong rồi về nhà
said maybe it was throat cancer, so my
bảo chắc là hay là ung thư vòng họng r
child took me to the Central ENT Hospital for
con nó lại đưa ra bệnh viện à tai mũ
examination, then to
Họng Trung ương khám xong lại sang viện
another hospital. I went to two different hospitals for a
ca nữa hai khám hai nơi sang viện ca xem
biopsy to see if there was
là xét nghiệm Sinh tiết xem là có ung
cancer. The doctor said it was a
thư hay không Thế bác sĩ bảo là u thanh
small laryngeal tumor. I went back to the ENT hospital and they
quả này vẫn nhỏ về bệnh viện Tai mũ họng
said there was no laryngeal tumor, so I went to
thì l bảo không có u thanh quản xuống
Bac Giang Hospital. My nephew
bệnh viện Bắc Giang Cái đứa cháu nhà em
works at a doctor's clinic at Bac Giang Hospital and he
nó làm ở bác sĩ bệnh viện Bắc Giang nó
said, "
bảo bây giờ Bá xuống dưới này để trưởng
Now, if you say it
Thanh khám bảo bây giờ như bà mà bảo
's a boy, who can predict it? If it's a girl, it's a
rằng là con trai có ai tiên là con trai
girl. A boy is a boy,
không phải con gái là con gái Con trai
whatever it is, it's a boy. There's a
là con trai cái gì có là bảo có Có u
laryngeal tumor, but you should just
thanh quản thế nhưng mà bác về bác cứ
rest." People say, "You're just having fun,
nghỉ ngơi Thắng riêng người ta bảo Thắng
you should go home and have fun." And then...
ăn chơi bác cứ về ăn chơi đi Xong rồi
When the 20 doctors came down here, I performed endoscopic surgery on them. After that, I went home and
đến 20 bác xuống đây em mổ cho bác nội
said, "Okay,
soi cho Bác Thế xong r em về em bảo thôi
I'll just go back to practicing meditation. I'm not going to have
em quay ra em tu tập thế chứ em không đi
surgery now." What if they say it's 50/50? Remember,
mổ B giờ Nhỡ người ta bảo 50 50 nhớ Chạm
if the larynx is damaged and I can't speak, then I'll just go back
mà cái thâ thanh quản lại không nói
to practicing the book of karma and
được thôi Thì về tu tập quyển số tá và
dedicate the merit to the karmic creditors. Because I've had
hồi hướng cho ă gia trái chủ bởi vì mình
so many illnesses before, and I've practiced
đã bao nhiêu bệnh tật mà đã từng tu tập
Karma Transformation and recovered
Chuyển Nghiệp hết cả rồi khỏi được hết
completely. Now, I'll just try this one, and see if it doesn't work. If not, it will still come back. I just have faith that I'm practicing, I'm eliminating karma, and the root of the illness is improving. So I've been practicing since
thuyên giảm Thế là tu tập suốt từ năm
last year, never leaving the book of
ngoái đến giờ chưa bao giờ rời quyển số
karma. Since last year, I have
tá Thế đến từ từ năm ngoái đến giờ cũng
n't had surgery, I haven't gone back to make offerings to the Three Jewels, I've made offerings to the karmic creditors. That's it, I'm going back to Ba Vang Temple. Since last year, I haven't had a hoarse voice, I haven't
ta cũng chẳng thấy khản tiếng cũng chẳng
felt anything, I haven't seen any laryngeal tumor.
thấy gì chả thấy đâu u thanh quản đâu
That's another karmic connection. I also want to
đấy là một nhân duyên nữa tôi cũng xin
tell my story to all fellow
kể câu chuyện của tôi cho các toàn thể
practitioners who deeply believe in Buddhism and diligently
đạo hữu những ai mà tin sâu Phật pháp
practice 100% Karma Transformation.  Karma
tinh tấn tu hành 100 ph Chuyển Nghiệp
doesn't manifest as physical illness. Uncle Lai had
không phải đi bệnh hiện thế là bác Lại
another illness, a laryngeal tumor, which he
thêm một bệnh nữa là u thanh quản quyết
decided not to have surgery for, but instead focused on spiritual practice. And it
định không mổ mà chỉ tu tập và nó đã
transformed, as evidenced by the fact that he no
chuyển hóa bằng cánh là thấy mình không
longer suffers from a hoarse throat. Yes, it's been two
bị khản cổ nữa Vâng năm ngoái đến giờ ha
years now, and nothing has happened. This is
năm mà không làm sao thì đây là một minh
proof of the diligent practice that
chứng cho cái việc tinh tấn tu tập để
transforms karma, just as Uncle Lai said: "I
chuyển nghiệp cũng như lời Bác nói là
hope all of us practitioners diligently
Mong các đạo hữu chúng ta tinh tấn tu
practice, so we must believe that if
tập nên chúng ta phải tin tin là chúng
we do evil, we will have evil consequences."
ta làm ác thì chúng ta có quả báo ác Bởi
Because of this, many people don't understand
vì thế này ạ mọi người thì không hiểu
what "enemies and masters" means. Actually,
thế nào là oan gia chấy chủ Thực ra bây
who is "us"—that is, do we have resentment towards
giờ ai ta là mình tức mình có oán oán
others? And if we have the opportunity for
người ta không Và mình nếu có cơ hội trả
revenge, will we take revenge?
thù Mình có trả thù không có phải không
The master of our resentment is our own mind.
thì oan ta chí chủ chính là cái tâm đấy
That is, the mind
Đấy cái tâm
that doesn't want others to infringe upon
mà không muốn người khác xâm phạm vào
us, the mind that seeks revenge when we suffer greatly,
mình cái tâm trả thù khi mình bị quá khổ
when others mistreat us.
khi người ta hành mình quá khổ thì chúng
We are the same. The mind of self-control and perfect contemplation—I
ta cũng vậy Tâm chế Hoàn quán mới nói
jokingly but truthfully say this: if a chicken
vui nhưng rất thật là thế này con gà nó
is
đang
alive and you cut its throat, you are very happy, but will
sống mình cắt cổ nó mình rất vui thế
it seek revenge?
niệu nó có trả thù không
Although we say the chicken doesn't
Tuy rằng mình nói là con gà nó không
know revenge, that's just what we say.
biết trả thù đấy là mình nói thế cũng
So, the tiger chases us,
như vậy con hổ nó đi nó đuổi mình nó
thinking we don't know how to retaliate,
nghĩ là mình không biết trả thu phải
right? The tiger chases us, eating
không con hổ nó đuổi mình nó ăn chân ăn
our legs and arms. If we're not dead, we
tay của mình Nếu mình chưa chết mình có
go back, find a way to kill it,
đi về mình tìm cách mình mình giết nó
right? But the tiger does
không có phải không Thế nhưng mà con hổ
n't know that we're taking revenge.
thì nó đâu có biết là mình có trả thù nó
That's why only the Buddha
thế cho nên là chỉ có đức phật mới biết
knows that all sentient beings have the
được rằng tất cả chúng hữu tình tâm thức
same angry and resentful mindset. All sentient beings
sân giận giống nhau Tất cả chúng Hữu
have the same greed, hatred, and delusion,
Tình có tâm tham sân si giống nhau cho
so they all seek revenge and cling to the
nên đều có sự trả thù đều có sự chấp
body, right? So, if we just
thân đúng không cho nên chúng ta chỉ cần
hit a dog, and it turns around and bites
đánh con chó thôi Nó quay lại nó làm sao
us, what kind of
nó cắn mình thì nó quay lại cắn mình là
mind is that? The mind of protection, the mind of revenge, right? It's the same
tâm gì tâm bảo vệ tâm trả thù phải không
here. We all do
Thế thì đây cũng thế tất cả chúng ta làm
evil things to sentient beings from many
các việc Ác Đối với chúng sinh từ nhiều
previous lives to this life. In fact, in
kiếp trước cho đến kiếp này Thực ra kiếp
this life, we also do too many evil things.
này chúng ta cũng làm quá nhiều việc ác
Shrimp, crabs, especially those crabs, are
con tôm con cua nhất là cái con cua ấy
alive. If you tear off
nó đang sống như thế xé một cái cái Mai
their shells, wouldn't that hurt, dear fellow practitioners?
của nó ra cô đau không có quý đạo hữu
Before, when we didn't know about Buddhism,
Hồi trước mình chưa biết đến phật pháp
we thought it was very normal, meaning we
mình thấy nó rất bình thường tức là mình
never felt
luôn luôn không cảm nhận được nỗi đau
their pain.  We are born into this world, but now that we
của chúng sinh thế nhưng bây giờ mình
know Buddhist teachings, we think about how
biết phật pháp rồi mình nghĩ đến cái
it is living. If we tear apart
chuyện nó đang sống như thế Mình xé cái
its flesh and bones, we know what it feels like. Does it hurt?
xương nó như thế nó có đau không thì nó
Does it seek revenge? It does seek revenge, and of
có trả thù không nó trả thù và đương
course, it will experience back pain, bone pain, and joint pain.
nhiên là việc đau lưng đau xương đau cốt
It will inevitably
của mình nó phải có phải không việc mình
suffer accidents and broken bones because of what
có thể tai nạn gãy xương là phải có vì
we did. But when
mình làm nó như vậy thế nhưng mà khi
we have merit, it won't seek revenge yet.
mình có phước thì nó chưa trả thù thôi
When our merit decreases, then
Còn khi mình giảm Phước thì các cơn đau
our pain is revenge, isn't
của mình đấy là trả thù thôi phải không
it? Therefore, as a Buddhist disciple, we
Thế cho nên là người đệ tử Phật thì tin
deeply believe in the concept of reincarnation and deeply believe
sâu sắc về vấn đề luân hồi và tin sâu
that once a mind is filled with resentment, it is all the
sắc rằng tâm một khi đã oán kết thì nó
same; it all has the desire for
đều giống nhau cả đều có cái m mong muốn
revenge and seeks every way to take revenge. And
trả thù và tìm mọi cách trả thù h và
we are always being retaliated against by
chúng ta thì luôn luôn bị trả thù bởi
all the beings we have
tất cả những chúng sinh mà mình đã gây
wronged. So, that is a truth.
tội ác cho họ cho nên đó là một sự thật
After we repent and believe in the
sau khi chúng ta sám hối và chúng ta tin
Buddha's teachings about praying for the deceased, that is,
lời Phật dạy về việc cầu siêu Tức là
we make offerings to the Three Jewels and dedicate the merit to the deceased. The
mình cúng dường tam bảo hồi hướng cầu
deceased will be liberated, and we will
siêu thì vong linh siêu thoát và mình sẽ
be transformed from illness. This is
được chuyển hóa bệnh tật thì đây là một
proof of this truth.  The point in
việc minh chứng cho cái quan điểm trong
Buddhism is that practicing leads to
Phật giả là như thế tu tập là có chuyển
karmic transformation and the liberation of souls,
nghiệp cầu siêu là vong linh được siêu
so I wish all the esteemed fellow practitioners
thoát thì cũng chúc các quý đạo hữu
in the Dharma assembly to be truly diligent.
trong đạo tràng thật là tinh